http://www.stmarykippax.org.uk/privacy-notices/

HOMECALENDARCHRISTMAS 2020SAFEGUARDINGNEW TO US?WHERE TO FIND USSERVICESNEWS AND COMING EVENTSEVENTS AND ACTIVITIESCONTACTSFOR FAMILIESBAPTISMSMARRIAGESBEREAVEMENT SUPPORTDATA PRIVACY NOTICESHISTORYST MARY'S CHURCH HALL & ALLERTON BYWATER CHURCH ANDONATIONSPHOTOSPHOTOSREVD ROSEMARIEâ€™S RETIREMENT JOAN WATKINS RETIREMENT (ALLERTON BYWATER)ARMISTICE DAY IN KIPPAX RIVER OF REMEMBRANCE AT ALLERTON BYWATERAFTERNOON TEA AT A/BYWATERHARVEST 2017 AT SWILLINGTONKIPPAX FLOWER FESTIVAL 2017ST MARY'S CHURCH HALL, KIPPAXST MARY'S, KIPPAXALLERTON BYWATER CHURCH STATIONS OF THE CROSS AT KIPPAXKIPPAX PARISH EVENTSLIBRARYAUDIOVIDEOLINKSSEARCH
HOME > DATA PRIVACY NOTICES
Data Privacy Notice of St Mary's
Church, Kippax
DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
The Parochial Church Council (PCC) of St Mary's Church, Kippax
Your personal data (information): Personal data relates a living individual who can be identified from that data. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the possession of the data controller. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the GDPR).
The PCC of St Mary's Church, Kippax, is the data controller. This means it decided how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
How do we process your personal data?
The PCC of St Mary's Church, Kippax, complies with its obligations under the "GDPR"
by keeping personal data up to date;
by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amount of data;
by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use personal data for the following purposes:
To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in a particular geographical  are as specified in our Constitution;
To administer membership  record;
To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity
To manage our employees and volunteers;
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running at St Mary's;
To share your contact details with the Diocesan office, so that they can keep you informed about news in the diocese and events, activities and services than will be occurring in the    diocese and in which you may be interested;
What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about diocesan events.
Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection lay, or a collective agreement;
Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided:
â—‹    the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in                        connection with those purposes);  and
â—‹    there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will only share your data with third parties outside the parish with your consent.
How long do we keep your personal data?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the "Keep or Bin: Care of your Parish Records at https://.churchofengland.org/more/libraries-and-archives/records-management-guides".
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data whilst it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to six years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.
Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
The right to request  a copy of your personal data which the PCC of St Mary's, Kippax, holds about you;
The right to request that the PCC of St Mary's, Kippax, corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the PCC of St Mary's, Kippax, to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the  processing at any time;
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing.
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commission Office.
Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints please contact the:
PCC Secretary: secretary@stmarykippax.org.uk
or Data Protection Person: dataprotectionperson@stmarykippax.org.uk
Printable Version
Allerton Bywater Data Privacy NoticeAllerton Bywater Data Privacy NoticeData Privacy Notice of St Mary's Church, SwillingtonData Privacy Notice of St Mary's Church, Swillington
This church website is powered by Church Edit| Privacy Notice
